Pablo Gabriel González Szczerb

pablo@pablogonzalezalba.com • +31 622704659

Summary

I am a Software Developer with over 7 years of experience in web development: I have worked with **Ruby on Rails**, **JavaScript**, **PHP**, and **MySQL**.

I am really good at looking at the big picture, I do not just settle with a spec to start developing. I want to get a deep knowledge about the product and the target users. I have learned that this previous research has saved countless hours of re-developing unwanted features.

Technical Skills

Ruby: I developed a web app with **Ruby on Rails** that serves *tens of thousands* of users monthly. I used **Rspec** and **Capybara** in order to achieve over 95% test coverage. I embrace the MVC pattern, but I know when to use Decorators, Services, and other classes to prevent fat Models.

Front-End: I have 6 years of professional experience developing frontend-heavy applications with **JavaScript**. Most of the time including layout with **HTML5** and **CSS3**. I have used mostly **jQuery** but lately it is not as important as it used to be. I am very happy with **Bootstrap** to achieve good looks with little effort. I have used **CoffeeScript** and lately I'm comfortable working with **ES7** and transpiling it with **Babel**.

PHP: I have developed web apps professionally for over 4 years and as a hobby for almost 10. I have worked with pure **PHP**, custom frameworks, custom CMSs, and **CakePHP**. I developed plugins for the latter and the experience widened my knowledge of MVC frameworks and helped me transition to **RoR**.

MySQL: I have designed relationals databases with complex schemas. I have also analyzed schemas and queries in order to improve their performances.

Others: I also have some experience with: Shell Scripting, Python, Haskell, Prolog, and C++.

Public projects: https://github.com/pablogonzalezalba

Experience

• Software Developer

Booking.com

12-2015 – Present

The world leader in booking accommodations online

- Backend development in the BookingSuite team.

• Freelance Developer

2010 - 2015

- Built small fully-functional custom web apps for small customers (products and employee administration).
- Worked with existing teams in migrating old applications to web back-ends with PHP.

Lead Developer

01-2014 - 07-2015

Pemasys – People Management System

SaaS Web App for HR

- Rebuilt the website of PortalRH and developed Pemasys using Ruby on Rails, and then led the team to develop new features:
 - * Serves tens of thousands of users monthly.
 - * Has an improved security against exploits.
 - * Went from nothing to over 95% test coverage.
 - * Uses a modern layout and mobile-first (with Bootstrap).
- Developed algorithms for automatically calculate résumé completeness and quality, and then used it to pair them with jobs, in order to suggest jobs to a candidate or to indicate the recruiter if it was a good match.

- Developed a simple bot that analyzed the résumés and suggested updates simulating being a human being. The resulting emails had an open rate of almost 50%.
- Encouraged code quality with a linter (Rubocop) and required code reviews.
- Taught and mentored new employees on Ruby on Rails.

• Software Developer

06-2013 - 01-2014

Dos al Cubo

CMS for Online Newspapers

- Did support fixing bugs and providing alternatives for the current and older versions of the CMS
- Developed new features/widgets for the CMS.
- Made a REST API to interact in the SaaS app.

• Software Developer

10-2009 - 05-2013

Sustantia

Software Factory

- Developed small enterprise web applications from the beginning through the end using CakePHP and MySQl.
 - * 2009 2010 By myself with the oversight of the lead developer.
 - * 2011 2013 Leading a team of up to 3 people.
- Reduced 4 times the time required to do prototypes and small first version of applications by developing templates and plugins for CakePHP.
- Taught and mentored new employees on PHP, MySQL, and the internal CMS.

Education

• M.Sc. Computer Science [incomplete]

2010 - 2015

Universidad de Buenos Aires

- 70% completed.
- Finished all subjects in the algorithms and theory branches.

Other Courses

• ¡Query Mobile and Phone Gap / Cordova

2012

- Using jQuery Mobile for smartphones design. While the concept is deprecated, the experience helped me when developing responsive websites.
- Using Phone Gap (now Apache Cordova) to create native apps for Android and iOS with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.